DANKO LOBOS BUSTAMANTE

Senior Computer Science Engineering Student

CONTACT

✓ dankollb@outlook.com

Santiago, Chile.

LinkedIn

EDUCATION

Civil Engineering in Computer Science

Metropolitan University of Technology 2022 - present

Bachelor's in Computer Science

University of Chile 2019 - 2021

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

C, Python, Java, C++.

WEB

Angular, Vue, HTML, CSS/SCSS, JavaScript, TypeScript.

DATABASE

MySQL, MS SQL Server., MongoDB.

OTHER

Git, Node.js, Docker, Postman, Bash.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Natural Language Processing.
- Data Mining.
- Agile Methodologies.
- Design Patterns.
- Object-Oriented Programming (OOP).
- Test Driven Development (TDD).
- Earned Value Management (EVM).

HUMAN SKILLS

- · Adaptability.
- Problem Solving.
- Collaboration.
- Detail Oriented.
- Effective Communication

IDIOMS

- Spanish Native.
- English Advanced.

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Last-year engineering student and big enthusiast for new technologies and their responsible use. Proficient worker experienced on projects related to web apps development, data science and Al. Interested in GenAl, NLP, Machine Learning and Cybersecurity. Continuous learner, focused to constantly grow as a professional and as a person.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack AI Developer (Intern)

Deliryum.AI

Oct 2024 - Dec 2024

- Company dedicated to offer artificial intelligence solutions based on computer vision for industrial security operations.
- I worked mainly in two projects:
 - AI: I supported in the dataset expansion process to improve the performance of detection models, In addition, I helped automate the data collection through scripts.
 - Web App: I implemented new functionalities within the web application that makes use of AI models.
- Tools: Angular, Python, JS/TS, Postman, MySQL.

Programmer (Trainee)

Alloxentric

Aug 2024 - Nov 2024

- University's partner technology company dedicated to offer omnichannel services to other companies, provides projects for the IT Project Management course as real practical experience.
- I worked in a team to implement functional improvements to a web application focused on human resources management.
- Tools: Vue.js, Python, JS/TS, Docker, MongoDB.

RESEARCH

1. Barbay, Jérémy & Freire-Fernández, Daniel & Lobos-Bustamante, Danko. (2022). Popping Up Balloons for Science: a Research Proposal. ACI '22: Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Animal-Computer Interaction. DOI: 10.1145/3565995.3566029.